Could you get by without using the internet for four and a half years?
你能四年半不用互联网也过得下去吗？
That’s exactly what singer and actress Selena Gomez has done in a bid to improve her mental health.
歌手兼演员赛琳娜·戈麦斯为了改善自己的心理健康，恰恰就是这么做的。
She has spoken extensively about the relationship between her social media usage and her mental wellbeing, recalling feeling like “an addict” when she became Instagram’s most followed user in 2016.
她曾详细谈论过自己使用社交媒体的情况与心理健康状况之间的关系，还回忆说，2016年成为Instagram上关注者最多的用户时，她觉得自己像个“瘾君子”。
“Taking a break from social media was the best decision that I’ve ever made for my mental health,” she says.
她说：“暂别社交媒体，是我为自己的心理健康做过的最好决定。”
“The unnecessary hate and comparisons went away once I put my phone down.”
“我一放下手机，那些无谓的恶意和比较就都消失了。”
Ditching the web at large, however, is a far more subtle and complicated prospect.
然而，要抛开整个互联网，就是一件微妙、复杂得多的事了。
The increasing digitisation of our society means that everything from paying a gas bill to plotting a route to a friend’s house and even making a phone call is at the mercy of your internet connection.
我们的社会日益数字化，这意味着从缴纳燃气费到规划去朋友家的路线，甚至打电话，一切都受制于你的网络连接。
Actively opting out of using the internet becomes a matter of privilege.
主动选择不使用互联网，就成了一件关乎特权的事。
Ms Gomez’s multi-millionaire status has allowed her to take the “social” out of social media, so she can continue to leverage her enormous fame while keeping the trolls at bay.
戈麦斯女士千万富翁的身份，让她得以把“社交”从社交媒体中剔除，这样她就可以继续利用自己的巨大名气，同时把恶意挑衅的帖子挡在门外。
The fact that she’s still the second most-followed woman on Instagram suggests it’s entirely possible to maintain a significant web profile to promote various projects—by way of a dedicated team—without being exposed to the cruel comments, hate mail and rape or death threats.
她至今仍是Instagram上关注者第二多的女性，这一事实表明，完全有可能借助一支专职团队，在网上保持可观的知名度来宣传各种项目，而不必遭受那些恶毒的评论、仇恨信件以及强奸威胁或死亡威胁。
It goes without saying that this is fundamentally different from how the rest of us without beauty deals and films to publicise use the likes of Instagram, TikTok and Twitter, but even the concept of a digital detox requires having a device and connectivity to choose to disconnect from.
不用说，我们其他人既没有美妆合约，也没有电影要宣传，使用Instagram、TikTok和Twitter这类平台的方式与她的做法有着根本的不同；但即便是数字戒瘾这一概念，也需要人先拥有设备和网络连接，才能选择与之断开。
The UK’s digital divide has worsened over the past two years, leaving poorer families without broadband connections in their homes.
过去两年里，英国的数字鸿沟不断加剧，致使较贫困家庭的家中没有接入宽带。
Digital exclusion is a major threat to wider societal equality in the UK, so witnessing companies like Facebook championing the metaverse as the next great frontier when school children are struggling to complete their homework feels particularly irritating.
在英国，数字排斥对更广泛意义上的社会平等构成重大威胁，因此，中小学生还在为完成家庭作业苦苦挣扎，Facebook这样的公司却把元宇宙吹捧为下一个伟大的前沿领域，目睹这一幕格外让人恼火。
Consequently, it’s worth bearing in mind that while deleting all social media accounts will undoubtedly make some feel infinitely better, many other people benefit from the strong sense of community that sharing platforms can breed.
因此，值得记住的是：虽然删除所有社交媒体账号无疑会让一些人感觉好上千百倍，但其他许多人则从分享平台所能孕育的强烈社群归属感中受益。
Internet access will continue to grow in importance as we edge further towards web 3.0, and greater resources and initiatives are needed to provide the underprivileged with the connectivity they desperately need to learn, work and live.
随着我们向Web 3.0进一步迈进，互联网接入的重要性将继续提升；要为弱势群体提供他们学习、工作和生活所急需的网络连接，就需要更多的资源和举措。
It’s crucial that people who feel that social media is having a detrimental effect on their mental health are allowed to switch off—and that those living in digital exclusion are able to switch on in the first place.
至关重要的是，要允许那些觉得社交媒体正对自己的心理健康产生有害影响的人断开网络，也要让那些遭受数字排斥的人首先能够接入网络。